Meet Patel

114 Eastville Avenue, Scarborough, Ontario / patel00446@gmail.com / +15147131906

Summary

Motivated student completing Bachelor's degree. Experienced in Agile and Scrum environments. Supports team administrative, project coordination, design and programming needs. Fluent in English. School projects included building apps, optimizing programs and validating code. Resourceful software developer with hands-on experience in software development and frameworks. Talented at object-oriented design, functional programming paradigms and various development languages. Demonstrated mastery of MERN as well as passion for continual learning.

Profiles

LinkedIn: https://bit.ly/linkedinmeetpatel

GitHub: https://bit.ly/gitmeetpatel

Portfolio: https://bit.ly/portfoliomeetpatel

Technical Skills

• Programming Languages: C#, C++, C, Java.

• Web Development: PHP, JavaScript, JQuery, BootStrap, HTML, CSS/SCSS.

- JS Frameworks: Node, Express, Angular, React and React Native.
- Databases : PostgreSQL, MySQL, MySQL Workbench and Microsoft SQL server.
- Software Familiarity: Microsoft Visual Studio, Android Studio, NetBeans, Slack, SQL, Visual Studio Code, Docker, Eclipse.
- Project Management : Agile Methodology, Scrum.
- Software Development : CI/CD Pipeline, API Design and Development
- Source and Version Control: Git, GitHub

Experience

Clickripple Digital Solution Inc. (July 2021 - Dec 2021)

Software Developer Intern, Toronto, Ontario

07/2021 - 12/2021

- Experience on various frontend technologies like React JS, React Native.
- Introduced methodologies and best practices that enhanced product definition, release processes and customization of applications to user needs.
- Deployed Front-end applications on Desktop and Mobile.
- Developed and coded on back-end technologies like Node JS and APIs.
- Used the latest styling libraries like Bootstrap, Material UI and used their components and styling for frontend technologies.

Milestone Technoconsulting Pvt. Ltd.

Web Application Developer, Ahmedabad, Gujarat 07/2019 - 12/2019

- Majorly worked on Reactjs projects and used React testing libraries for unit tests.
- Having a good hand on backend also we used Nodejs(Express) to build APIs.
- As a Database, we used Postgres Database and can handle MySql databases.
- Contributed software engineering expertise in the development of products through the software lifecycle, from requirements definition through successful deployment.

Education

ACS Diploma, Programming And Web Technologies

Institut Supérieur D'Informatique, Montreal, Quebec 01/2022

Bachelor of Information Technology

Birla Vishwakarma Mahavidhyalaya, Anand, Gujarat 06/2019

Academic Projects

Online Examination System: (Technologies Used: Reactjs, Nodejs, Mysql)

- The main purpose of developing this project was to create a dynamic atmosphere for conducting examinations and it was developed by four people and my main role was to develop frontend using react.
- We have used react js as frontend and node js as backend and we have used xampp as a database server. We have
 also used Agile technologies to develop our website and Github for version control and the intermediate to share
 code.

Library Management System: (Technologies Used: PHP, Mysql)

- Main Objective of our project was to create a dynamic atmosphere to track books of college i.e., who has taken the book and when is the return and issues date of the book the work was done under the faculty who guided with the working environment of the project.
- We have used HTML, CSS3 and Bootstrap for the frontend and our website was responsive too and our backend was designed with PHP and we have used mysql server.

Dating-site: (Technologies Used: PHP, Mysql)

- Purpose of this website was to create a dynamic atmosphere for the user to date online and to make new friends and it can also give the freedom to text the end user.
- Frontend was builded with the help of Bootstrap 4 and HTML and backend was designed with PHP and mysql database was used.

Many more project was done during academic studies like:

• Android Application : E-commerce application

C#: Shopping Cart
Java: E-Shop Website
JS: Quiz-Web-Application
Reactjs-Nodejs: Music Playlist